<resources>
    <string name="app_name">LingVels</string>
    <string name="greeting_text1">WELCOME TO</string>
    <string name="greeting_text2">LINGVELS</string>
    <string name="start">Start</string>


    <string name="text1_1">Ba-room, ba-room, ba-room, baripity, baripity, baripity, baripity — Good.</string>
    <string name="text1_2">His dad had the pickup .....</string>
    <string name="text1_3">He could get up now. Jess ..... out of bed and into his overalls.</string>
    <string name="text1_4">He didn’t worry about a shirt because once he began running he would be hot as popping grease</string>
    <string name="text1_5">even if the morning air was chill, or shoes because</string>
    <string name="text1_6">the bottoms of his feet were by now as tough as his worn-out sneakers.</string>
    <string name="text1_7_maybelle">“Where you going, Jess?“</string>
    <string name="text1_8">May Belle lifted herself up sleepily from the double bed where she and Joyce Ann slept.</string>
    <string name="text1_9_jess">“Sh!“</string>
    <string name="text1_10">The walls were thin. Momma would be mad as flies in a fruit jar if they woke her up this time of day.</string>
    <string name="text1_11">He patted May Belle’s hair and yanked the twisted sheet up to her small chin.</string>
    <string name="text1_12_jess">“Just over the cow field.“</string>
    <string name="text1_13_maybelle">“Gonna run?“</string>
    <string name="text1_14_jess">“Maybe.“</string>
    <string name="text1_15">Of course, he was going to run.</string>
    <string name="text1_16">He ..... up early every day all summer to run.</string>
    <string name="text1_17">He figured if he worked at it, he could be the fastest runner in the fifth grade when school opened up.</string>
    <string name="text1_18">He had to be the fastest—not one of the fastest or next to the fastest, but the fastest. The very best.</string>
    <string name="text1_19">He tiptoed out of the house. The place was so ..... that it screeched whenever you put your foot down.</string>
    <string name="text1_20">But Jess had found that if you tiptoed, it gave only a low moan,</string>
    <string name="text1_21">and he could usually get outdoors without waking Momma or Ellie or Brenda or Joyce Ann.</string>
    <string name="text1_22">May Belle was another matter. She was going on seven, and she worshiped him, which was OK sometimes.</string>
    <string name="text1_23">He began to trot ..... the yard. His breath was coming out in little puffs — cold for August.</string>
    <string name="text1_24">But it was early yet. By noontime when his mom would have him out working, it would be hot enough.</string>
    <string name="text1_25">Miss Bessie stared at him sleepily as he climbed across the scrap heap, over the fence, and into the cow field.</string>
    <string name="text1_26_missbessie">“Moo—oo.“</string>
    <string name="text1_27_jess">“Hey, Miss Bessie. Just go on back to sleep.“</string>
    <string name="text1_28">Miss Bessie strolled over to a greenish patch and yanked up a mouthful.</string>
    <string name="text1_29_jess">“That’a girl. Just eat your breakfast. Don’t ..... me no mind.“</string>
    <string name="text1_30">He always started at the northwest corner of the field, crouched over like the runners he had seen on Wide World of Sports.</string>
    <string name="text1_31">He took off flying around the cow field.</string>
    <string name="text1_32">Miss Bessie strolled toward the center, still following him with her droopy eyes, chewing slowly.</string>
    <string name="text1_33">His straw-colored hair flapped hard against his forehead, and his arms and legs flew out every which way.</string>
    <string name="text1_34">He ..... to run properly, but he was long-legged for a ten-year-old, and no one had more grit than he.</string>
    <string name="text1_35">Lark Creek Elementary was short on everything, especially athletic equipment,</string>
    <string name="text1_36">so all the balls went to the upper grades at recess time after lunch.</string>
    <string name="text1_37">So the lower-grade boys had started this running thing.</string>
    <string name="text1_38">They would all line up on the far side of the lower field and race to a line they’d toed across at the other end.</string>
    <string name="text1_39">One time last year Jesse had won. Not just the first heat but the whole shebang.</string>
    <string name="text1_40">Only once. But it had put into his mouth a taste for winning.</string>
    <string name="text1_41">For the rest of that day, and until after lunch on the next,</string>
    <string name="text1_42">he had been “the fastest kid in the third, fourth, and fifth grades,” and he only a fourth grader.</string>
    <string name="text1_43">On Tuesday, Wayne Pettis had won again as usual.</string>
    <string name="text1_44">But this year Wayne Pettis would be in the sixth grade.</string>
    <string name="text1_45">Anybody had a chance to be the fastest runner, and by Miss Bessie, this year it ..... be Jesse Oliver Aarons, Jr.</string>
    <string name="text1_46">He could hear the third-grade boys screaming him on.</string>
    <string name="text1_47">They would follow him around like a country-music star. Even his dad would be proud.</string>
    <string name="text1_48">Jess rounded the corner. His body was begging him to quit, but Jess pushed it on.</string>
    <string name="text1_49">He had to let that puny chest of his know who was boss.</string>
    <string name="text1_50_maybelle">“Jess!”</string>
    <string name="text1_51">She was yelling from the other side of the scrap heap.</string>
    <string name="text1_52_maybelle">“Momma says you gotta come in and eat now. Leave the milking til later.”</string>
    <string name="text1_53">Oh, crud. He’d run too long. Now everyone would know he’d been out and start in on him.</string>
    <string name="text1_54_jess">“Yeah, OK.”</string>
    <string name="text1_55">He turned, still running, and headed for the scrap heap.</string>
    <string name="text1_56">Without breaking his rhythm, he climbed over the fence, thumped May Belle on the head, and trotted on to the house.</string>
    <string name="text1_57_ellie">“We-ell, look at the big Olympic star!”</string>
    <string name="text1_58">Ellie banged two cups onto the table, so that the strong, black coffee sloshed out.</string>
    <string name="text1_59_ellie">“Sweating like a knock-kneed mule.”</string>
    <string name="text1_60">Jess pushed his damp hair out of his face and plunked down on the wooden bench.</string>
    <string name="text1_61">He dumped two spoonfuls of sugar into his cup and slurped to keep the hot coffee from ..... his mouth.</string>
    <string name="text1_62_brenda">“Oooo, Momma, he stinks. Make him wash.”</string>
    <string name="text1_63">Brenda pinched her nose with her pinky crooked delicately.</string>
    <string name="text1_64_mother">“Get over here to the sink and wash yourself.”</string>
    <string name="text1_65_mother">“And step on it. These grits are scorching the bottom of the pot already.”</string>
    <string name="text1_66_brenda">“Momma! Not again!”</string>
    <string name="text1_67">Lord, he was tired. There wasn’t a muscle in his body that didn’t ache.</string>
    <string name="text1_68_ellie">“You heard what Momma said.”</string>
    <string name="text1_69_brenda">“I can’t stand it, Momma! Make him get his smelly self off this bench.”</string>
    <string name="text1_70">Jess put his cheek down on the bare wood of the tabletop.</string>
    <string name="text1_71_mother">“Jess-see! And put on a shirt.”</string>
    <string name="text1_72_jess">“Yes’m.”</string>
    <string name="text1_73">He dragged himself to the sink. The water he flipped on his face and up his arms ..... like ice.</string>
    <string name="text1_74">His hot skin crawled under the cold drops.</string>
    <string name="text1_75">May Belle was standing in the kitchen door watching him.</string>
    <string name="text1_76_jess">“Get me a shirt, May Belle.”</string>
    <string name="text1_77_maybelle">“You shouldn’t ought to beat me in the head.”</string>
    <string name="text1_78">And she went off obediently to fetch his T-shirt. Good old May Belle.</string>
    <string name="text1_79">Joyce Ann would have been screaming yet from that little tap. Four-year-olds were a pure pain.</string>
    <string name="text1_80">His mother announced as they were finishing the grits and red gravy.</string>
    <string name="text1_81_mother">“I got plenty of chores needs ..... around here this morning.”</string>
    <string name="text1_82">His mother was from Georgia and still cooked like it.</string>
    <string name="text1_83">Ellie and Brenda squawked in concert.</string>
    <string name="text1_84_ellie">“Momma, you promised me and Brenda we could go to Millsburg for school shopping.”</string>
    <string name="text1_85_mother">“You ain’t got no money for school shopping!”</string>
    <string name="text1_86_brenda">“Momma. We’re just going to look around. Christmas! You don’t want us to have no fun at all.”</string>
    <string name="text1_87_ellie">“Any fun.”</string>
    <string name="text1_88_mother">“Oh, shuttup.”</string>
    <string name="text1_89">Ellie ignored her.</string>
    <string name="text1_90_ellie">“Miss Timmons is coming by to pick us up. I told Lollie Sunday you said it was OK.“</string>
    <string name="text1_91_ellie">“I feel dumb calling her and saying you changed your mind.”</string>
    <string name="text1_92_mother">“Oh, all right. But I ain’t got no money to give you.”</string>
    <string name="text1_93_brenda">“I know, Momma. We’ll just take the five dollars Daddy promised us. No more’n that.”</string>
    <string name="text1_94_mother">“What five dollars?”</string>
    <string name="text1_95_ellie">“Oh, Momma, you remember.”</string>
    <string name="text1_96">Ellie’s voice was sweeter than a melted Mars Bar.</string>
    <string name="text1_97_ellie">“Daddy said last week we girls were going to have something for school.”</string>
    <string name="text1_98_mother">“Oh, take it.”</string>
    <string name="text1_99">Mother angrily reached for her cracked vinyl purse on the shelf above the stove and counted out five wrinkled bills.</string>
    <string name="text1_100_brenda">“Momma, can’t we have just one more? So it’ll be three each?”</string>
    <string name="text1_101_mother">“No!”</string>
    <string name="text1_102_brenda">“Momma, you can’t buy nothing for two fifty. Just one little pack of notebook paper’s gone up to…”</string>
    <string name="text1_103_mother">“No!”</string>
    <string name="text1_104">Ellie got up noisily and began to clear the table.</string>
    <string name="text1_105_ellie">“Your turn to wash, Brenda.”</string>
    <string name="text1_106_brenda">“Awww, Ellie.”</string>
    <string name="text1_107">Ellie jabbed her with a spoon. Brenda shut up her mouth.</string>
    <string name="text1_108">She wasn’t ..... smart as Ellie, but even she knew not to push Momma too far.</string>
    <string name="text1_109">Which left Jess to do the work as usual.</string>
    <string name="text1_110_mother">“All right, Jesse. Get your lazy self off that bench.”</string>
    <string name="text1_111_mother">“Miss Bessie’s bag is probably dragging ground by now. And you still got beans to pick.“</string>
    <string name="text1_112_jess">“OK, Momma. I’m going.”</string>
    <string name="text1_113">It was May Belle who came to tell him in the bean patch that people were moving into the old Perkins place down on the next farm.</string>
    <string name="text1_114">Jess wiped his hair out of his eyes and squinted. Sure enough.</string>
    <string name="text1_115">A U-Haul was parked right by the door. One of those big jointed ones.</string>
    <string name="text1_116">These people had a lot of junk. But they wouldn’t last.</string>
    <string name="text1_117">The Perkins place was one of those ratty old country houses you moved into</string>
    <string name="text1_118">because you had no decent place to go and moved out of as quickly as you could.</string>
    <string name="text1_119">He thought later how peculiar it was that here was probably the biggest thing in his life, and he had shrugged it off as nothing.</string>
    <string name="text1_120">The flies were buzzing ..... his sweating face and shoulders.</string>
    <string name="text1_121">He dropped the beans into the bucket and swatted with both hands.</string>
    <string name="text1_122_jess">“Get me my shirt, May Belle.”</string>
    <string name="text1_123">The flies were more important than any U-Haul.</string>
    <string name="text1_124">May Belle jogged to the end of the row and picked up his T-shirt from where it ..... discarded earlier.</string>
    <string name="text1_125">She walked back holding it with two fingers way out in front of her.</string>
    <string name="text1_126_maybelle">“Oooo, it stinks!”</string>
    <string name="text1_127_jess">“Shuttup!”</string>
    <string name="text1_128">He grabbed the shirt away from her.</string>

    <string name="task1_pers1">Jess</string>
    <string name="task1_pers2">May Belle</string>
    <string name="task1_pers3">Miss Bessie</string>
    <string name="task1_pers4">Ellie</string>
    <string name="task1_pers5">Mother</string>
    <string name="task1_pers6">Brenda</string>
    <string name="task1_pers7">May Belle</string>


    <string name="option2_1">to go</string>
    <string name="option2_2">going</string>
    <string name="option2_3">gone</string>

    <string name="option3_1">slid</string>
    <string name="option3_2">slidded</string>
    <string name="option3_3">slided</string>

    <string name="option16_1">had gotten</string>
    <string name="option16_2">has gotten</string>
    <string name="option16_3">gets</string>

    <string name="option19_1">old</string>
    <string name="option19_2">damp</string>
    <string name="option19_3">rattly</string>

    <string name="option23_1">between</string>
    <string name="option23_2">across</string>
    <string name="option23_3">away</string>

    <string name="option29_1">pay</string>
    <string name="option29_2">give</string>
    <string name="option29_3">get</string>

    <string name="option34_1">had never learned</string>
    <string name="option34_2">have never learned</string>
    <string name="option34_3">never learned</string>

    <string name="option45_1">will</string>
    <string name="option45_2">was going to</string>
    <string name="option45_3">is going to</string>

    <string name="option61_1">scalding</string>
    <string name="option61_2">freezing</string>
    <string name="option61_3">boiling</string>

    <string name="option73_1">stabbed</string>
    <string name="option73_2">nailed</string>
    <string name="option73_3">pricked</string>

    <string name="option81_1">be done</string>
    <string name="option81_2">doing</string>
    <string name="option81_3">to do</string>

    <string name="option108_1">such</string>
    <string name="option108_2">as</string>
    <string name="option108_3">so</string>

    <string name="option120_1">on</string>
    <string name="option120_2">outside</string>
    <string name="option120_3">around</string>

    <string name="option124_1">had been</string>
    <string name="option124_2">was</string>
    <string name="option124_3">has</string>


</resources>